Once you install Android Studio, you can open it and
check for updates before proceeding. Then we can configure Android Studio.
Open up the Android SDK Manager to see what tools, platform versions, and
components we have installed. At the time of this recording,
the Android L platform is available but it's still in developer preview mode.
That means it's subject to change until the official release. You can't upload
your app to Google Play if it's targeting this L platform version.
Hence, we want to use the latest stable platform version which is KITKAT or
API level 19. API level 20 is for Android ware or watches and not for
phones or tablets. Deselect all the other packages. And just choose the ones for
API level 19. We want the SDK as well as the system images for the emulator.
We also want the Android Support Library for backwards compatibility. For
the most up-to-date version of all the packages you need to install,
check the link below. Otherwise, continue with installing the packages.
Accept the license and then install. Then we can click and
create a new project. In the Project Wizard, we set the app name to be Sunshine.
Then we provide a corresponding package name. For distribution purposes,
the package name should be globally unique across packages installed on Android.
To avoid conflicts, you can use the reverse of the internet domain that you own.
This follows the Java package naming conventions. Note that we're also using
the com dot example namespace for our Sunshine app since it's a sample, but
you cannot publish an app on Google play that uses this namespace.
Usually leaving the default package name that's suggested is fine. However,
this class was originally filmed with an older version of Android Studio which
added the app module at the end of the package name. So go ahead and
make this change now if you want your code to match the rest of the code in
the course. Then we do the project location and
we hit next. Now, we need to choose our minimum SDK version.
In previous versions of Android Studio, you would also have to
select the target SDK. But now the Project Wizard automatically sends the target
SDK to be the latest version. Even though target SDK is already selected for
you, it's important to know the distinction between min and target SDK